sodastreamusa.com 2019-04-10

# Legal – SodaStream

Copyright Notices

© SodaStream USA Inc. All Rights Reserved.

PEPSI, the Pepsi Globe, SIERRA MIST and CREATED BY US. MADE BY YOU. are trademarks of PepsiCo, Inc. and are used under license.

Country Time®, Crystal Light®, Kool-Aid® and the Kool-Aid man design are registered trademarks of Kraft Foods used under license.

Ocean Spray® is a registered trademark of Ocean Spray Cranberries, Inc., used under license.

"Welch’s" and the "Family Farmer Owned" banner are registered trademarks of Welch Foods, Inc., used under license. ©2016 Welch's.

We process orders within 48 hours of receipt on business days. Once the order has processed, our goal is to ship your order within 48 hours.

Terms and Conditions

**Last updated: May 29, 2018**

SodaStream USA Inc. provides services to you when you visit or shop at sodastream.com (“SodaStream's Website”), use SodaStream products or services through SodaStream's website, use SodaStream applications for mobile, or use software provided by SodaStream in connection with any of the foregoing (collectively, "SodaStream Services"). SodaStream provides SodaStream Services subject to the following conditions.

**By using SodaStream Services, you agree to these conditions. Please read them carefully.**

**OUR CONTRACT**

An order placed on the SodaStream Website is an offer to SodaStream to buy the SodaStream product(s) in the order. When you place an order to purchase a product from SodaStream through SodaStream's Website, we will send you an e-mail confirming receipt of your order and containing the details of your order (the "Order Confirmation E-mail"). The Order Confirmation E-mail is acknowledgement that we have received your order, and does not confirm acceptance of your offer to buy the product(s) ordered. We only accept your offer, and conclude the contract of sale for a product ordered by you, when we dispatch the product to you. Your contract is with SodaStream USA Inc. Without affecting your right of withdrawal set out in section 2 below, you can cancel your order for a product at no cost any time before we dispatch your order.

**RETURNS**

Yes, we offer a money-back guarantee on Sparkling Water Makers only purchased on sodastreamusa.com. If you are not satisfied with your Sparkling Water Maker for any reason, you may return it, postmarked within 30 days of date of purchase (please keep your dated receipts) for a full refund of the total cost of the merchandise you ordered, plus any applicable sales tax. Valid on sodastreamusa.com purchases ONLY. (SodaStream does not refund initial or return shipping charges.) Sparkling Water Makers purchased as holiday gifts between November 1 and December 31 may be returned through January 31. Our Sparkling Drink Mixes, Carbonating Bottles, CO2 Cylinders and accessories cannot be returned or exchanged if purchased from sodastreamusa.com. If you wish to make a return, please contact SodaStream Customer Support at 1-800-763-2258 or by clicking Support on the website.

**PRICING AND AVAILABLITY**

All orders are charged applicable sales tax based on the ship-to destination zip code and city. SodaStream USA Inc. is registered to collect sales tax in all US continental states. If you have a sales tax exemption, please submit a support request by clicking Support on the website in order to have you tax refunded on your recent order. Formal documentation must be provided in accordance with your state's policy on tax exemptions in order for your request to be honored.

As we process your order, we will inform you by e-mail as soon as possible if any products you order are currently unavailable. If you are charged for these products and they are not able to be dispatched to you, you will be refunded within 30 days.

Please note that unless otherwise stated on the SodaStream Website, delivery estimates are just that. They are not guaranteed delivery times and should not be relied upon as such.

SodaStream will not be held responsible for any delay or failure to comply with our obligations under these conditions if the delay or failure arises from any cause which is beyond SodaStream's reasonable control. This condition does not affect your right to have the products sent to you within a reasonable time. If the delay occurs before the products are dispatched, we will not charge you for the products until they are dispatched and you may cancel your order at any time prior to dispatch. 

**PRIVACY**

Please review our Privacy Policy below, which also governs your use of SodaStream Services, to understand our practices in relation to how we handle your personal information.

**ELECTRONIC COMMUNICATIONS**

When you use any SodaStream Services, or send e-mails to us, you are communicating with us electronically and you consent to receive communications from us electronically. We will communicate with you by e-mail or by posting general notices on the SodaStream Website. You agree that all agreements, notices, disclosures and other communications that we provide to you electronically satisfy any legal requirement that such communications be in writing.

**LICENSE AND ACCESS**

Subject to your compliance with these Conditions of Use and your payment of any applicable fees, SodaStream or its content providers grant you a limited, non-exclusive, non-transferable, non-sub-licensable license to access and make personal and non-commercial use of the SodaStream Services. This license does not include any resale or commercial use of any aspect of the SodaStream Services, or its contents; any collection and use of any product listings, descriptions, or prices; any derivative use of any SodaStream product provided or its contents; any downloading or copying of account information for the benefit of another merchant; or any use of data mining, robots, or similar data gathering and extraction tools. All rights not expressly granted to you in these Conditions of Use are reserved and retained by SodaStream. No part of the SodaStream Website may be reproduced, duplicated, copied, or otherwise exploited for any commercial purpose without express written consent of SodaStream. You may not frame or utilize framing techniques to enclose any trademark, logo, or other proprietary information (including images, text, page layout, or form) of SodaStream without express written consent. You may not use any meta tags or any other "hidden text" utilizing SodaStream's name or trademarks without the express written consent of SodaStream. You may not misuse the SodaStream Services. You may use the SodaStream Services only as permitted by law. The licenses granted by SodaStream terminate if you do not comply with these Conditions of Use.

**YOUR ACCOUNT**

If you use SodaStream Services, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account and password and for restricting access to your computer or mobile device, and you agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur under your account or password. SodaStream reserves the right to refuse service, terminate accounts, remove or edit content, or cancel orders in its sole discretion.

**PRODUCT DESCRIPTIONS**

SodaStream attempts to be as accurate as possible. However, SodaStream does not warrant that product descriptions or other content of any SodaStream Service are accurate, complete, reliable, current, or error-free. If a SodaStream product purchased from the SodaStream website is not as described, you should contact SodaStream Customer Service department at 1.800.763.2258 or by clicking Support on the website

**ORDER PROCESSING**

We charge your credit card immediately upon order placement.

We do not ship to PO boxes or APO addresses or internationally. We do not ship to Puerto Rico, Alaska or Hawaii. We reserve the right to refuse any orders which are paid for by international credit cards and to refuse service to any account or individual that we believe may be utilizing fraudulent credit card details.

**OTHER BUSINESSES**

SodaStream partners with certain third parties that provide links to the SodaStream Services and it does not assume any responsibility or liability for the actions, product, and content of all these and any other third parties. You should carefully review their privacy statements and other conditions of use.

**DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY**

THE SODASTREAM SERVICES AND ALL INFORMATION, CONTENT, MATERIALS OR PRODUCTS INCLUDED ON OR OTHERWISE MADE AVAILABLE TO YOU THROUGH THE SODASTREAM SERVICES ARE PROVIDED BY SODASTREAM ON AN "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" BASIS, UNLESS OTHERWISE SPECIFIED IN WRITING. SODASTREAM MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, AS TO THE OPERATION OF THE SODASTREAM SERVICES, OR THE INFORMATION, CONTENT, MATERIALS OR PRODUCTS INCLUDED ON OR OTHERWISE MADE AVAILABLE TO YOU THROUGH THE SODASTREAM SERVICES, UNLESS OTHERWISE SPECIFIED IN WRITING. YOU EXPRESSLY AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE SODASTREAM SERVICES IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK.

TO THE FULL EXTENT PERMISSIBLE BY APPLICABLE LAW, SODASTREAM DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. SODASTREAM DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE SODASTREAM SERVICES, INFORMATION OR CONTENT INCLUDED ON OR OTHERWISE MADE AVAILABLE TO YOU THROUGH THE SODASTREAM SERVICES, SODASTREAM'S SERVERS OR SERVERS PROVIDED BY THIRD PARTY COMPANIES FOR SODASTREAM OR ELECTRONIC COMMUNICATIONS SENT FROM SODASTREAM ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS. SODASTREAM WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OF ANY KIND ARISING FROM THE USE OF ANY SODASTREAM SERVICES, OR FROM ANY INFORMATION, CONTENT, MATERIALS, PRODUCTS OR OTHER SERVICES INCLUDED ON OR OTHERWISE MADE AVAILABLE TO YOU THROUGH THE SODASTREAM SERVICES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, PUNITIVE, AND CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, UNLESS OTHERWISE SPECIFIED IN WRITING.

CERTAIN STATE LAWS DO NOT ALLOW LIMITATIONS ON IMPLIED WARRANTIES OR THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF CERTAIN DAMAGES. IF THESE LAWS APPLY TO YOU, SOME OR ALL OF THE ABOVE DISCLAIMERS, EXCLUSIONS, OR LIMITATIONS MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU, AND YOU MIGHT HAVE ADDITIONAL RIGHTS.

**DISPUTE RESOLUTION BY BINDING ARBITRATION.**

**PLEASE READ CAREFULLY. IT AFFECTS YOUR RIGHTS.**

(A). Any dispute, controversy or claim arising out of or relating to any SodaStream product including, but not limited to, claims of personal injury and/or property damage, shall be submitted to arbitration administered by the American Arbitration Association in accordance to its then existing Consumer Arbitration Rules. The AAA Rules are available online at www.adr.org, or by calling the AAA at 800.778.7879.   The Federal Arbitration Act (Title 9 of the U.S. Code) shall govern the interpretation, enforcement, and proceedings relating to this arbitration.

(B). Arbitration is more informal than a lawsuit in court. It uses a neutral arbitrator instead of a judge or jury, allows for more limited discovery than in court, and is subject to very limited review by courts. Arbitrators can award the same damages and relief that a court can award. By agreeing to arbitration, the parties understand and agree that they are waiving their rights to maintain other available resolution processes, such as a court action or administrative proceeding, to settle their disputes.

(C). Any claim shall be brought only in the party's individual capacity, and shall not in any case be brought by the party as a plaintiff or class member in any purported class or representative proceeding.

(D). A party who intends to seek arbitration must first send to the other, by certified mail, a written Notice of Dispute ("Notice"). The Notice to SodaStream should be addressed to SodaStream's Corporate Office located at 136 Gaither Dr, Ste 200, Mount Laurel, NJ 08054 ("Notice Address"). The Notice must (a) describe the nature and basis of the claim or dispute; and (b) set forth the specific relief sought. If an agreement to resolve the claim is not reached within 30 days after the Notice is received, any party may commence an arbitration proceeding. During the arbitration, the amount of any settlement offer made by a party shall not be disclosed to the arbitrator.

(E). There shall be one arbitrator. The arbitrator shall have the power to rule on his or her own jurisdiction, including, but not limited to, any objections with respect to the existence, scope, or validity of the arbitration provision or to the arbitrability of any claim or counterclaim.   The arbitrator's award shall be binding on all parties, and judgment upon the award may be entered by any court of competent jurisdiction.

**APPLICABLE LAW**

By using any SodaStream Service you agree that applicable federal law and the laws of the state of Delaware will govern these Conditions of Use other than in relation to a dispute which will be addressed in accordance with Condition 12 above.

**MODIFICATION, AND SEVERABILITY**

We reserve the right to make changes to our site, policies, and these Conditions of Use at any time. If any of these conditions shall be deemed invalid, void, or for any reason unenforceable, that condition shall be deemed severable and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of any remaining condition.

**WAIVER**

If you breach these Conditions of Use and we take no action, we will still be entitled to use our rights and remedies in any other situation where you breach these Conditions of Use.

**OUR CONTACT DETAILS**

SodaStream's corporate address is 136 Gaither Dr, Ste 200, Mount Laurel, NJ 08054

If you have any questions about SodaStream Services or have questions about a SodaStream product, please contact SodaStream's Customer Service department at 1.800.763.2258 or by clicking Support on the website.

SODASTREAM - PRIVACY STATEMENT

**Notice last updated: 22.5.2018**

**1.  ** **Our Commitment To Privacy**

Your privacy is very important to us at SodaStream and its affiliates, hereinafter also **"we"** and/or **"us"** and/or **"SodaStream"** ). To better protect your privacy we provide this notice ( **"Privacy Notice"** ) explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personal data may be requested.

1.1               We strongly urge you read this notice and make sure you fully understand our practices in relation to personal data, before you access or use any of our services. If you read and fully understand this Privacy Notice, but remain opposed to our practices, you must immediately leave our website, and avoid or discontinue all use of any of our Services. Where you have read this notice but would like further clarification, please contact us at [privacy@sodastream.com](mailto:privacy@sodastream.com).

**2.  ** **Important information**

2.1               The purpose of this Privacy Notice is to provide you with clear explanation of what personal data we collect, when, why and how we collect, use and share your personal data and it explains your statutory rights. This Privacy Notice is not intended to override the terms of any contract you have with us, nor any rights you might have under applicable data privacy laws.

2.2               Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information on our website or offline from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13\. Parents and guardians should supervise their children's activities at all times. If we learn we have collected or received personal data from a person under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a person under 13, please contact us at [privacy@sodastream.com](mailto:privacy@sodastream.com).2.3               Note that our website contains links to third party websites which we are not responsible for. Please review the privacy policies of such third party websites should you visit these websites. This Privacy Notice does not address the privacy or information practices of any third parties.

2.4               Our website uses cookies and other tracking technology to automatically collect certain data concerning its interactions with visitors. Some of this information may include personal data. We explain more about the information we collect using cookies and tracking technology in paragraph 10.3.                  

**3\. What information do we collect and how do we collect it?**

3.1               Personal data is collected when you voluntarily submit it through a website form, if you register with or use one of our website or online services. Our website automatically collects certain data concerning its interaction with visitors that facilitate operation, management and planning. Some information that may constitute personal data (such as your browser type, operating system, IP address, domain name, number of times you visited the website, dates you visited the website, date and time of an online request, the time required to download information you requested, error codes generated while your browser is in contact with our website and the amount of time you spent viewing the website) may be collected via cookies and other tracking technologies, all on an anonymised basis. Aggregate Information (such as how many times visitors log onto our website) may also be collected. We explain more about our use of cookies and tracking technologies in paragraph 10.3.1.1  If you register or contact us as an individual, we will collect your name, email address, telephone number, address information (together, **"identification data"** ); information about your household ( **"household composition data"** ), the consumption habits of you and members of your household ( **"consumption data"** ), information about the device you use to access our website or online services ( **"device data"** ), payment and credit card information ( **"payment data"** ), information to set up and access your SodaStream account ( **"login data"** ); or

3.1.2                      If you register or contact us on behalf of a company, we will collect company identification data, identification data from the company representative, company composition and consumption data, device data, payment data and login data.

3.2               If you contact us by other offline methods in order to buy our products or services or by using one or more of the contact means provided offline, we will collect identification and payment data as relevant for the sale and delivery of the goods and services or to respond to your query or complaint and, as far as necessary, for the handling and fulfillment of the order and ongoing provision of our services.

3.3               If you engage with us through social media e.g. Water Blog, Recipe Site, Facebook, Pinterest, Twitter, we collect login information and any personal data you voluntarily provide, such as opinions in blog or recipe entries, or messages you post on our social media pages. If you upload content, including your personal data, to a social network and then tag our website, your submission will be subject to that social network's terms of use and privacy notice, even where you post on an official SodaStream page on the social network. We do not have control over these terms of use and privacy policies, and have not reviewed their adequacy. You should therefore review these before submitting any personal data.

3.4               If you apply to one of our open positions published in our careers sites, by sending us contact details and CV ( **"applicants personal data"** ) via the relevant application on our website, or through any other means provided by us (e.g. social media),we will collect such applicants personal data in order to process your application.

**4.  ** **How do we use your personal data?**

4.1               To provide our products and services We collect personal data in order to offer our products and/or services and their functions. We may use the information collected in order to validate your order or subscription, to process your payment (for instance of a monthly fee in the case of a subscription) and to provide the products and services that you requested, ordered or to which you subscribed. We will also use your personal data as far as necessary for the handling and fulfilment of your order as well as to provide customer support.We also use this information for customer management purposes, to maintain our relationship with you, with a view to providing stellar customer experience.

4.2               To verify your identity We may use the information collected from you to verify your identity. We may also use this information to establish and set up your account, verify or re-issue a password, log your activity and contact you from time to time;

4.3               For internal business purposes such as:

4.3.1                      to improve our products in order to make them fit for our customers' needs and to draw insights in relation to possible improvements;

4.3.2                      to improve our services to you and customize your browsing experience. Some of the information (particularly the information collected by cookies and other tracking technology) helps us improve our website; and

4.3.3                      to track any fraudulent activities and other inappropriate activities and monitor content integrity on our website.

4.4               To process job applications We collect applicants personal data solely for SodaStream's internal recruitment purposes including for: identifying applicants, evaluating their applications, making hiring and employment decisions, and contacting applicants by phone or in writing.

4.5               To communicate with you We use your personal data to respond to your queries and/or complaints about our products or services, and to provide you important information about your account and your products e.g. to inform you that your payment has been accepted or your order has been processed.

**5.  ** **Carrying out Direct Marketing:** We may use your personal data, including information related to your order, such as your address for direct marketing purposes. We may for example send you emails to inform you of news and updates about our products and services. This may be in the form of email, post, SMS, telephone or targeted online advertisements. Where required by law, we will obtain your consent prior to sending you such marketing information.

5.1               To protect your privacy and ensure you have control over the use of your personal data, we will always give you the opportunity to "opt out" of direct marketing when you contact us in relation to a product or service or you receive any email, text or other direct marketing communication. 5.2               You have a right to prevent direct marketing of any form at any time - this can be exercised by following the opt-out link attached to each communication, by changing privacy settings within your SodaStream account or by sending an email to [privacy@sodastream.com](mailto:privacy@sodastream.com). If you want to review or update the information you have provided us, you can click "my profile" at our website's home page, and edit the information. If you have not been asked already to provide your email address and a password, we will ask you to do it before changes are made, so as to prevent others from accessing and altering your personal data.

5.3               Based on the information we have about you, we take steps to limit direct marketing to a reasonable and proportionate level, and to send you communications which we believe may be of interest or relevance to you, based on the information we have about you.

**6.  ** **Legal basis for processing personal data:**

6.1               We will only collect, use or share your personal data for the purposes set out in this Privacy Notice where we are satisfied that:

6.1.1                      our use of your personal data is necessary to perform a contract or take steps to enter into a contract with you. For example, in order to provide our product and our services it will be necessary for us to process certain personal data such as your address, phone number, identification data and payment data to create your user account or fulfill your order. Also, we carry out this processing for the purpose of knowing our customer and maintaining our relationship with you, with a view to providing a stellar customer experience; or6.1.2                      our use of your personal data is necessary to support legitimate interests that we have as a business to provide products and services to our customers, provided it is conducted at all times in a way that is proportionate, and that respects your privacy rights. For example, we strive to always improve our products and services in order to make them fit our customers' needs. For this reason, we process personal data such as consumption habits, device information and household composition and draw insights in relation to possible improvements; or

6.1.3                      our use of your personal data is necessary to comply with a relevant legal or regulatory obligation that we have. For example, to maintain appropriate business records, to comply with lawful requests by public authorities and to comply with applicable laws and regulations or as otherwise required by law; or

6.1.4                      you have provided your consent to us using your personal data for that purpose (e.g. where you provide us with marketing consents or opt in to additional services).Where the basis of processing is your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent, and therefore prevent that processing, at any time.

**7.  ** **How we protect and store your personal data**

7.1 Data Security

7.1.1                      To prevent unauthorised access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. Some of the steps we take are: placing confidentiality requirements on our staff and service providers; destroying or permanently anonymising personal data if it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected. Sodastream will comply with applicable laws in the event of any breach of the security, confidentiality or integrity of your personal data and, where we consider appropriate or where required by applicable law, notify you via email, text or conspicuous posting on our website in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, in so far as it is consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement, or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system. 7.1.2                      However, the security of personal data depends in part on the security of the device used to communicate with us, the security you use to protect your login information, and the security provided by your internet access service provider. We make commercially reasonable efforts to make the collection and security of information consistent with this Privacy Notice and all applicable laws and regulations. Where you have a SodaStream username, login or password, you are responsible for keeping this information confidential. We ask you not to share a username, login or password with anyone.

7.2               Data Retention

7.2.1                      We may retain your data as long as necessary to provide our products and services, and beyond such time to the extent legally permitted and based on our legal obligations (e.g. in relation to invoice retention) or legitimate interests (eg in retaining data for the purposes of responding to possible disputes or complaints or for possible reactivation of subscriptions).

7.2.2                      In addition, we maintain a data retention policy which we apply to information in our care. Where your data is no longer required we will ensure it is securely deleted or anonymised. 7.2.3                      Please note that SodaStream may retain applicants personal data submitted to it for no longer than two years after the applied position has been filled or closed.  This is done so we could re-consider applicants for other positions and opportunities at SodaStream; so we could use their information as reference for future applications submitted by them; and in case the applicant is hired, for additional employment and business purposes related to his/her work at SodaStream. If you previously submitted applicants personal data to SodaStream, and now wish to access it, update it or have it deleted from SodaStream's systems, please contact us at [privacy@sodastream.com](mailto:privacy@sodastream.com).

**8.  ** **We may share your personal data  **SodaStream may share your personal data with third parties (or otherwise allow them access to it) only in the following manners and instances:

8.1               to other SodaStream affiliates for the purposes mentioned in this Privacy Notice.

8.2               with any third parties to whom the relevant SodaStream entity subcontracts all or part of this processing. The purpose of this transfer will be to help manage our business and deliver services.  For instance, we may transfer your personal data to a service provider to the extent necessary to complete an order and deliver your product. Other instances may include transfers to e-marketing service providers, hosting providers and any other relevant roles.  Note that we will never sell your personal data to a third party. These third parties have agreed to confidentiality restrictions and use any personal data we share with them or which they collect on our behalf solely for the purpose of providing the contracted service to us.

8.3               where permitted by local data protection laws, SodaStream may disclose or otherwise allow others access to your personal data pursuant to a legal request, such as a subpoena, legal proceedings, search warrant or court order, or in compliance with applicable laws, if we have a good faith belief that the law requires us to do so, with or without notice to you. If warranted, we may also allow access to this information in special emergencies where physical safety is at risk.

8.4               we may disclose any personal data or other information obtained from or about you, to third parties in connection with a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or sale of all or substantially all of our assets, to the extent that this is necessary for the process.

**9.  ** **Transferring personal data globally**

9.1               Your personal data may be transferred and stored outside your place of residence, that are subject to different standards of data protection. In particular, if you live in the EU, you should be aware that your personal data may be shared with, and transferred to, SodaStream affiliates and third-party service providers who are located outside the EU. We will take appropriate steps to ensure that transfers of personal data are in accordance with applicable law and carefully managed to protect your privacy rights and interests and transfers are limited to countries which are recognised as providing an adequate level of legal protection or where we can be satisfied that alternative arrangements are in place to protect your privacy rights.  To this end:

9.1.1                      we will ensure that transfers within SodaStream and its affiliates will be covered by an agreement entered into by members of SodaStream Group (an intra-group agreement) which contractually obliges each member to ensure that personal data receives an adequate and consistent level of protection wherever it is transferred within the Group;

9.1.2                      where we transfer your personal data outside SodaStream or to third parties who help provide our products and services, we will obtain contractual commitments from them to protect your personal data. Some of these assurances are well recognised certification schemes like the EU - US Privacy Shield for the protection of personal data transferred from within the EU to the United States; or

9.1.3                      where we receive requests for information from law enforcement or regulators, we will carefully validate these requests before personal data is disclosed.You have a right to contact us for more information about the safeguards we have put in place (including a copy of relevant contractual commitments) to ensure the adequate protection of your personal data when this is transferred as mentioned above.

**10.  ** **Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies  **

SodaStream uses certain monitoring and tracking technologies (such as cookies, beacons, pixels, tags and scripts). These technologies are used in order to maintain, provide and improve our services on an ongoing basis, and in order to provide our customers with a better experience. For example, thanks to these technologies, we are able to maintain and keep track of our customers' preferences and authenticated sessions, to better secure our services, to identify technical issues, user trends and effectiveness of campaigns, and to monitor and improve the overall performance of our services.Please note that third party services placing cookies or utilizing other tracking technologies through our services may have their own policies regarding how they collect and store information. Such practices are not covered by our Privacy Notice and we do not have any control over them.

10.1           Cookies

10.1.1                  Our website uses cookies, web beacons and similar technologies (" **Cookies** ") to track information provided to us by your browser when you use our website. Cookies are small text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded and may be stored on any of your devices that enable internet usage e.g. your computer, smartphone or tablet - like a memory for a web page. We use several different types of cookies.

10.2           We use the following cookies on our website: 

10.2.1.1            necessary cookies Necessary cookies are essential and help you navigate our website. This helps to support security and basic functionality and are necessary for the proper operation of our website, so if you block these cookies we can't guarantee your use or the security during your visit. 

10.2.1.2            functionality cookies Functionality cookies are used to provide you the best user experience. These cookies are, for instance, used to personalise content for you in line with your location. It also allows our website to remember choices made (like turning off use of cookies or which location you have previously selected) to provide more personal features.

10.2.1.3            performance cookies Performance cookies help us to understand the behaviour of users of our website. This allows us to continuously improve our website to provide the best information in support of our project aims. These cookies are also used to help us understand how effective our website is. For instance these cookies tell us which pages visitors go to most often and if they get error messages from web pages.

10.2.1.4            All of the Cookies are managed by third parties, and you may refer to the third parties' own website privacy notifications for further information. In particular, we use Google Analytics, which allow us to assess how you and other web users use our website, and this information is essential in helping us to continuously improve our website's functionality. They can be preserved from 30 minutes to two years. The information generated by these cookies about your use of our website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google Inc on servers in the United States.

10.3           Control your cookie settings: Once you have given us your agreement to the use of cookies, we shall store a cookie on your computer or device to remember this for next time. Internet browsers allow you to change your cookie settings, for instance to block certain kinds of cookies or files. You can therefore block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies.  However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies, you may not be able to access all or parts of the website, due to the fact that some may be functionality cookies. For further information about deleting or blocking cookies, please visit: <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/>.

**11.  ** **Your rights in relation to your personal data**

11.1           Subject to paragraph 11.2, certain exemptions, and in some cases dependent upon the processing activity we are undertaking, you have the following rights in this paragraph:

11.1.1                  to request that we provide you with a copy of your personal data that we hold and you have the right to be informed of; (a) the source of your personal data; (b) the purposes, legal basis and methods of processing; (c) the data controller's identity; and (d) the entities or categories of entity to whom your personal data may be transferred;

11.1.2                  to request that we cease processing your personal data, in whole or in part, as you direct us, for any purpose, save to the extent it is lawful to do so without consent;

11.1.3                  to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data where: (a) the accuracy of the personal data is contested; (b) the processing is unlawful but you object to the erasure of the personal data; (c) we no longer require the personal data for the purposes for which it was collected, but it is required for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim;

11.1.4                  to request that we erase your personal data in limited circumstances where it is no longer necessary in relation to the purpose(s) for which it was collected or processed; 11.1.5                  to challenge processing which we have justified on the basis of a legitimate interest;

11.1.6                  to request that we not transfer your personal data to unaffiliated third parties for the purposes of direct marketing or any other purposes;

11.1.7                  to request that we change the manner in which we contact you for marketing purposes;

11.1.8                  to request that we correct any errors in your personal data; 11.1.9                  to request that we update your personal data as required.  Note that you may also correct, update or remove certain parts of such personal data by yourself, or completely deactivate your SodaStream account, through your account settings;

11.1.10              to obtain a copy of the safeguards under which your personal data is transferred outside the EU; and

11.1.11              to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority for data protection.

11.2           We may ask you for additional information to confirm your identity and for security purposes, before disclosing the personal data requested to you. We reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for instance if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive.

**12.  ** **Changes to this Privacy Notice  **We may update and change this privacy statement from time to time, to keep it up to date with legal requirements and the way we operate our business. Please regularly check these pages for the latest version of this Privacy Notice.

**13.  ** **Contact information**

13.1           If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice or wish to exercise any of your rights as described in paragraph 11, you can contact us at:email address: [privacy@sodastream.com](mailto:privacy@sodastream.com) We will attempt to resolve any complaints regarding the use of your Personal data in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

13.2           For EU Member State residents, you also have a right to lodge a complaint with your national data protection supervisory authority at any time.  However, we encourage you to first contact us.
